Finding aid to Janet Olmsted papers CA.MS.00355
Smith College Archives
Janet Olmsted papers
1920-1997
Smith College Archives
Olmsted, Janet, 1904-1997
CA.MS.00355
0.833 linear feet (2 containers)
This collections contains primarily correspondence between Janet Olmsted and her family, as well as other parties. Also included in these papers are news clippings, photographs, and study notes.
Biographical / Historical
Janet Olmsted was born to Marguerite and John M. Olmsted on September 20, 1904 in Buffalo, New York. She was raised in Sardinia, New York with her two brothers, Prescott and John. Throughout her attendance at Smith College, she was active in athletics, holding a leadership position in the college's Athletic Association. She earned her Bachelor's of Arts from Smith in 1927, and returned to earn her Masters of Arts in Teaching from Smith's Graduate School in 1929.
Janet married Cabray Wortley, who she had steadily dated throughout her time at Smith, in September 1929. She was employed as a teacher from 1929 to 1933 at the Francis W. Parker School in Chicago. In 1934, she and her husband moved to St. Joseph, Missouri, where they raised three sons. She held jobs in a variety of fields in St. Joseph. In 1947, Janet divorced Wortley.
In order to care for her father in his old age, she moved to Pasadena, California in 1955. There, she was employed in sales for over two decades. She was very active as a parishioner of All Saints Episcopal Church, where she met Halleck J. Hoyt. He became her second husband in 1973. They remained married until her death in January 1997.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains primarily letters written by Janet to members of her family (namely, her father John M. Olmsted, her mother Marguerite, her brothers Prescott and John). The collection includes correspondence from 1920, when she was attending high school, to 1997, when her son advised Smith College of her death. Her most regular correspondence spans the years of 1923 through 1930, when she wrote to her family on a daily and weekly basis. The collection also includes correspondence between members of the Olmsted family with various other parties. Additionally, the collection contains some newspaper clippings, photographs, notes from her studies at Smith College, and her obituary.
Conditions Governing Access
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Janet Olmsted papers were donated to the College Archives by Priscilla Brewer in December 2009.
Smith College - Alumni and alumnae - History - Sources
- Photographs, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, July 1920 - November 1920 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, October 1923 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, May 1924 - October 1924 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, November 1924 - December 1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, January 1925 - May 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, October 1925 - December 1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, January 1926 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, February 1926 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, March 1926 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, April 1926 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, May 1926 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, June 1926 - July 1926 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, September 1926 - October 1926 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, November 1926 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, December 1926 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, January 1927 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, February 1927 - March 1927 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, April 1927 - May 1927 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, June 1927 - July 1927 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Correspondence, October 1927 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Correspondence, November 1927 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Correspondence, January 1928 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, February 1928 - March 1928 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, March 1928 - September 1928 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Correspondence, October 1928 - December 1928 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, January 1929 - April 1929 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Correspondence, May 1929 - June 1929 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence, June 1930 - September 1930 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Correspondence, April 1933 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, February 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, February 1997 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Correspondence, Undated; October - December (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Correspondence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 18)